## **Arturs Vaitilavics**

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPERFOR

## ABOUT ME

I have been working in Global visual effects (VFX) companies for over 10 years, VFX is closely related to programming, and I have always used bits of code to automate mundane everyday tasks. Writing scripts became my favourite part of my work, and I decided to study Java, Python and C#.

Quick learner, patience, responsibility and Procedural aproach are the qualities that I have developed over the years of work and studies.



## EDUCATION

## Software Development Academy

Java from Scratch (378 hours) | April 2020 - Jan 2021

- # Java # GIT # Coding
- # Software Testing TDD # Databases SQL, NoSQL
- # JDBC, Hibernate, MongoDB Java Driver
- # HTTP # Server Basics # HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- # JSP and Servlets # Introduction to JVM
- # Spring Framework # Scrum Methodology

Final project description: This project will be a platform that can be used by different companies to track, update, approve their employees holidays. Technologies: Java, Spring, MySql, React Github Link:

https://github.com/artursvaitilavics/com.holidays\_av

## Liepajas Universitate

Computer Sciences | Jan 2007 - Dec 2009 # C++, #Visual Basic, #ActonScript

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 3D (CG) Generalist

OLV | Apr 2019 - present

- Work with C# for Unity
- Render pipeline tasks with Python
- Visual scripting with Unreal Blueprints

**Achievements:** In game enemy AI with C#, and addons for Blender/Python, Sped up 6 weeaks work to 2 weeks, by implementing Python script for autmating complex tasks. **Developed skills:** Communication with Developer team,

Python, C#, Abstract classes, Git

## Vfx Compositor

UPP | Sep 2018 - Apr 2019

- Small Python scripts to increase my output in working with Foundry's Nuke

**Achievements:** Sped up workfolw for similar vfx space shots.

**Developed skills:** Python in production

## HOW TO CONTACT ME

City: Riga

Email: artyvt@gmail.com Phone: +371 24224 071

LinkedIn:

**Arturs Vaitilavics** 

Github:

arturs vaitilavics

Private repositories available upon request.

# TECHNOLOGICAL SKILLS

- Java
- Python
- C#
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- Spring Boot
- Angular
- React
- Python Blender API
- Spring
- Hibernate
- Junit
- Mockito

## LANGUAGES

Latvian, English = Fluent Russian = Basic

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Animation Compositor**

Blue Zoo Animations | Jul 2018 - Sep 2018 - Lighting and Compositing with Maya and Nuke

## **Animation Compositor**

Doodle Productions | Nov 2017 - Jul 2018 - Compositing with Nuke

## **Animation Compositor**

Arx Anima | Jul 2017 - Nov 2017 - Compositing with Nuke

## **CG** Generalist

Blue Zoo Animations | Apr 2017 - Jun 2017 - Lighting with Maya, Compositing with AfterEffects

#### **CG** Generalist

Freelance/Self-Employed | Mar 2016 - Apr 2017

- 3D Modeling, lighting and animation with Maya
- Compositing with Nuke

Achievements: Deliverd 2 CG projects

**Developed skills:** Learned 5 VFX softwares for Animation, Compositing, Modeling and Texturing

## Stereoscopic 3D (S3D) trainer

Prime Focus | Aug 2015 - Mar 2016

- Traing teams while in production

**Achievements:** Trained over 300 junior to senior 3D

artists

**Developed skills:** Communication with groups over 30

people large.

## S3D and VFX Generalist

Freelance/Self-Employed | Nov 2014 - Aug 2015 - Implement new tehnologies to improve quality and production speed.

## S3D Lead

Prime Focus | Aug 2010 - Nov 2014

- Leading team of artist
- Help and Problem solve complex tasks
- QA my teams output and scripts

Achievements: Lead teams of 12 people while working

on Big budget Hollywood movies.

**Developed skills:** Communication, responsibility, Various VFX software skills. Ability to give tasks, and check the quality.